So, you're going to go ahead and try to actually create a composable using the factory pattern because the single thing will not make sense for a fetch function.
Right? You're going to have a new URL, you're probably parsing.
And basically, you know, from what you've seen in the code base with the fetch see what you can, how much you can refactor it, how far you want to get.
As, as if anyone has ever written their own fetch function, you probably know it's a very deep rabbit hole of like configuration of methods and stuff.
So, my offering to you is just keep it simple to start, right? If you only get as far as like getting the response and JSONifying you and that's it, like that's still something.
Do not try to like write a full fetch fetch function. There are people who are very good at that and they do that for us already.
This is more for more so for the practice than anything else.
So, what we're going to do, I mentioned this earlier in the exercise, but we're going to do a simplified version of fetch because again, it's a pretty complicated one.
And then I did realize later on when I was updating that we had done already a lot with the use week composable, so in the event you're looking for, you know, actually kind of want practice.
The use task composable is one that doesn't really use a store design pattern because we ended up kind of using that as the model.
We're looking for an additional practice, we'll if you do that, but let's go ahead and just take a look at what a used fetch composable might look like.
So, as we can see here, we're looking at the code base. There is a lot of native fetch happening.
And so, the goal with the use such composable when I asked this, and my apologies are not being clear with this, it's less so that we're not necessarily trying to replicate the fetch API itself.
But over taking a look at kind of what's happening, it's fairly consistent in the sense that like, let's see, in this one, for example, it's fetching two weeks.
It has some custom options regarding a post in the app like the format type, but then it always stringifies the week and then it like checks the response so can throws an error.
This pattern is fairly consistent.
We see it here as well with the fetch weeks. Here we go fetch API base URL weeks. If response is not okay, throw error, then await that the fetch weeks is JSON.
And then basically, this is what we want, right? They're like, this is what I want to return.
So, the idea here is I think a simplified version of you've used fetch would probably package something like this all together.
So that it just returns exactly what we want at the end of it.
So the way I would go about this is, actually, let's go ahead and copy this while I'm at it since I'm ready in here, is we'll go inside of our composables folder and we'll create a use fetch.
And the reason we're doing it, you might be wondering, why in composable is because I intend on returning a reactive obviously plan on using views or reactivity as part of this.
So, and so you have a choice here, right? You might be thinking, oh, well, could I do like a single ten for this, right? Like use fetch equals something, but use fetch is a function.
So you're kind of inherently going to be using a factory function for this kind of composable because ultimately you're not really trying to share a state between your fetches.
It's, there are some things we'll share which we'll see very shortly, but otherwise, yeah, so a couple things, okay, so here's what we want to export.
We know this thing is definitely consistent, so this is an example of something that like really just sits outside.
So if you I base URL and I believe we have it already.
And then actually for those wondering what that was, that was a ray cast clipboard history, so you can search through it, it's pretty nice.
And then, okay, so we got that.
And so basically here, I find that people generally tend to include the slash when they're doing like their URLs.
So as a result, I'm just going to do a URL that's going to be a string.
And then what are we going to return, we're going to return.
Actually, I don't actually know the actually we mentioned that we're not going to do too much with types right now.
Okay, so this is where then this part kind of comes into play.
So we're putting that inside of the use fetch.
So we're going to pass it basically the API base URL, although I don't need to do it this way actually, API base URL, plus URL.
That's what we're appending. Oh, this needs to be a sync because we have an await inside of here.
So then we say, okay, throw error. Yep, this is a generic thing, right, if throw an error, if the response is not okay.
Otherwise, what we're going to do here, and this is where we're going to be more generic size, we're going to.
Return of weight response.
That should do the trick. I read it correctly.
Okay, the main other thing I need to do is I do like to do the maybe reference getter, so I'm going to drop that here of string.
Okay, and here I think we have a basic use best function.
And so the way we can test this is we can go ahead and basically import use fetch from our new composable.
And again, let's go ahead and do it like this.
Composibles like that.
That way it's this more consistent.
All right, then from here, we now know we no longer need all of this.
We should get is to be able to await used fetch weeks.
I believe it was weeks.
Oh, is this the one on the had it?
Yes, it was right.
Okay, weeks, and then that's it.
Okay, so if this works as intended, where we're using use week, we're currently using it.
Let's see, it looks like we're using it inside of the planner.
So I'll wait, not just using the composable.
Where's the fetch fetch week being called.
We're calling it, okay, looks like we're calling it inside of task form model.
So this is what where we'll test it.
Server is down.
So let's call that.
Let me switch branches before I forget.
Get check out.
Oh, five solution.
Okay, cool.
We're up and running.
And then if we go ahead and take a look at our task.
And then.
Wait.
Oh, task model.
That's what it is.
So I need to edit it.
But.
Okay, now something's funky.
What if you suddenly return weeks from your.
So I did not return weeks from then use the use fetch function.
You didn't actually return weeks from that.
Uh-huh.
Right.
So then basically what we need to do then here.
Cons.
Well, yes.
Right.
I mean, we could say this.
Is that everything?
I believe so.
Okay.
Let's see if it's shot.
We refresh.
We edit the task.
Mm-hmm.
What's yelling at me?
Probably which I said would not define during instance based model.
Okay, so something with the weeks is not being defined correctly.
You changed the value that was there.
This one.
Correct.
So we thought value equals.
It was called something else prior to that.
Was it?
Uh-huh.
That was being said.
Okay.
Last.
It was.
fetched weeks.
Use just a name of the response.
All right.
Was it? Okay.
Yeah.
Isn't that fetch weeks?
It looks identical.
Yeah.
So that looks.
The signature looks right.
So it must be a way that I implemented this.
That's causing it to not.
I mean.
Easiest thing.
He's just logged the response real quick.
Uh, clear.
Refresh.
That's.
That's it.
Right here.
Uh, oh, maybe it's just not.
Yeah.
So that's being done.
Did we have to go like to refer to value with the, with the URL that we passed in?
That is a good question.
Right now it is, you're totally right.
We did not follow that pattern because the use fetch right now is using a maybe.
But it actually, for now, it actually is assuming.
Uh, your L value.
It is assuming that.
But I will make sure this is at least consistent.
I'd print out it's entirely possible that this is broken three exercises ago and not realized.
Oh, that is totally true.
Yes.
This is totally fair.
Um, so I mean, let's see, where's that console log living is living in use week.
So yeah, this is totally fair.
Let's see.
Well, actually, if anything, we shouldn't.
The planner should at least have it.
So the planner here.
Okay.
So let's let we know of planner.
We're working right now.
So let's go ahead and take a look at that.
So planners here.
Oh, it weeks right now is being brought in.
Actually, this kind of interest.
Oh, because it's doing its own fetch here.
Okay.
So we're going to knock this out.
And we're going to see if we can get it to work.
We're going to create week store, which we did not import.
I'll use week store, right?
And then here, console week store equals use week store.
Okay.
That's that.
Then it freshes the weeks.
Handle week created.
Then this also then needs a week store.
That fetch weeks.
And anything else?
Yep, one more week store.
That fetch weeks.
Okay.
I think that's everything.
Yeah.
That looks good.
Okay.
It looks like this is fine.
So like you said, there's probably something that's going finicky on the
side.
We're not doing full refactors.
And so there we have an example of kind of a, again, overly simplified use fetch function.
Again, if you're going to do this, at least look at what the next team is doing.
There's a bunch of people who already have these sort of composable fetch functions that are very, very robust.
Configurable handles all the methods, blah, blah, blah.
Great patterns.
So be sure to check that out.
Bye-bye.